tapresearch.com 2017-12-07

# TapResearch: Privacy Policy

This privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) describes the information collected by TapResearch, Inc. (“we,” “us,” or “our,” including our affiliates and subsidiaries), how we collect that information, how that information may be used, and with whom it may be shared. By accessing or using our website, http://www.tapresearch.com (the “Website”), participating in our surveys, or using other products or services we provide (collectively, “Services”), you are accepting the practices set forth in this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with this Privacy Policy, then you must not access or use the Services. Our Services may be offered through or in connection with third party mobile applications or third party websites. When you participate in the Services you are leaving the third party mobile application or website through which you accessed the Services. 

#### Information Collected and Method of Collection

Information collected is relevant for the purpose for which it is to be used and, to the extent necessary, TapResearch takes reasonable steps to ensure that data is reliable for intended use, accurate, complete, and current. 

**Information collected automatically:** When you use the Services, we automatically collect and store information about your computer or mobile device and your online activities (“Response Metadata”), which we transfer and store in accordance with the provisions contained in this Privacy Policy. Response Metadata may include: 

  * _Device Information/Specifications._ Technical information about your computer or device (e.g., type of device, web browser or operating system, IP address, etc.). 
  * _Geographic Location._ We use your IP address to derive your computer or device's approximate geographic location. 
  * _Time, Length and Extent of Usage._ When you use the Services, how long you use a Service for (e.g., how long it takes you to answer a survey question) and which Services feature(s) and/or function(s) you use. 
  * _Cookies:_ We may use cookies to keep track of some types of information while you are using the Services. Cookies are very small files placed on your computer, which allow us to perform analytics, such as counting the number of users of the Services and distinguishing repeat users from new or unique users. Cookies help provide additional functionality to the Services and help us analyze usage of the Services more accurately, such as user preferences or trends (e.g., the Services may set a cookie on your browser allowing you to bypass engagement with a survey due to your previous completion of a survey). We rely on cookies for the proper operation of the Services; therefore if your browser is set to reject cookies, the Services may not function properly. If you refuse cookies from the Services, you assume all responsibility for any resulting loss of functionality or benefits with respect to the Services. 
  * _Mobile Device ID:_ We collect mobile device identifiers, such as Apple’s Identifier for Advertising ID (IDFA) or Google’s Android Advertising ID (AAID), to help us identify you within a mobile application and match you with appropriate survey opportunities. 
  * _Web Beacons:_ We may use web beacons in email communications in order to understand the behavior of our users. “Web beacons” (also known as “clear gifs” and “pixel tags”) are small transparent graphic images that are often used in conjunction with cookies in order to further personalize the Services for our users and to collect a limited set of information about our users. 

**Information you provide to us:** We collect information that you submit to us voluntarily through the Services. 

**_User Profile Information_ **

Before you fill out a survey, we ask that you create a user profile to help us match you with a survey. When you fill out a user profile, we collect certain information, including demographic information such as postal code, gender, marital status, education, ethnicity/race (where permitted by applicable law), employment related information, and non-personally identifiable information on household members, household income, age, etc. 

**_Registration Information_ **

If you choose to sign up for an account, we also collect additional information from you, including: 

  * Name
  * Email address
  * Username and password

**_Survey Information_ **

Occasionally, we host surveys for our survey partners and collect the information submitted through these surveys. We do not own this information and any information you choose to provide is used in accordance with the survey partner’s privacy practices. 

**_User Feedback_ **

If you provide us with comments, suggestions, recommendations or other feedback pertaining to our Services (collectively “Feedback’), you understand that we may (although we have no obligation to do so) retain, disclose, use, or otherwise commercially exploit that Feedback in connection with any or all of our Services without any compensation or consideration to you. 

**_Developer Information_ **

We may collect certain information from our developer partners at the time of registration and in connection with your use of the Services, including your name, email address, company name, app title(s), as well as financial information such as Tax ID, VAT or sales tax registration number or any other relevant tax number and payment information (e.g., bank account and routing number for ACH purposes). 

#### How We Use Your Information

Pursuant to the terms of this Privacy Policy, we may use the information we collect from you for the following purposes:

  * To process, analyze, and develop survey data for use with the Services and our third party customers;
  * To improve upon the surveys and delivery of our surveys through the Services;
  * To prevent fraud and other illegal activities;
  * To monitor and analyze trends, usage, and activities;
  * To communicate with you about the Services; and
  * To provide, maintain, and improve the Services and our overall business.

Where required by law, we obtain your prior opt-in consent at the time of collection for the processing of (i) personal information for marketing purposes and (ii) personal information deemed sensitive pursuant to applicable law. 

You can opt-out and instruct us not to send you marketing communications by e-mail by clicking on the unsubscribe link within the marketing emails you receive from us or by contacting us at support@tapresearch.com. Under the Privacy Shield provisions, it is your right to access, correct, or delete your personal data. If you wish to do so, please contact support@tapresearch.com. 

You may also withdraw any consent you previously provided to us, or object at any time on legitimate grounds to the processing of your personal information by contacting us at support@tapresearch.com. We will apply your preferences going forward. In some circumstances, withdrawing your consent to our use or disclosure of your personal information will mean that you cannot take advantage of certain products, services, surveys or promotions we may offer. 

#### Sharing Your Information

We will not otherwise sell, license or share your personal information to/with any other party(s) for commercial purposes, except as described below: 

  * To our third party service providers who provide services such as website hosting, data analysis, information technology and related infrastructure provision, customer service, email delivery, auditing, and other services. 
  * We may share User Profile Information and Response Metadata (collectively, the “Response Data”) and related information with survey creators and researchers, and with app developers (i.e., our customers). We may also share Response Data with unaffiliated third parties for their own internal purposes, including marketing purposes. If you wish to opt-out of having your information shared with these Third Parties, please contact support@tapresearch.com. 
  * We may share Survey Information with survey creators and researchers. 
  * We may share User Profile Information with third party sample/market research companies (each a “Third Party MR Company”) for the purpose of (i) identifying survey opportunities that you may be eligible for through the Third Party MR Companies and (ii) audience measurement projects or activities in connection with any online ad effectiveness program(s) operated or conducted by or on behalf of the Third Party MR Companies. In connection with online ad effectiveness programs, cookies or related technologies are used to identify advertisements that an individual has seen or interacted with for the purpose of ad survey recall work and audience measurement reporting/research. 

The Third Party MR Companies may share your social-demographic information with their clients or vendors in connection with the purposes set forth above. We will not share your name, email address, or phone number with the Third Party MR Companies. If you have any questions about this data sharing or wish to opt-out of having your information shared with Third Party MR Companies, please contact support@tapresearch.com. 

  * To an acquirer, successor, or assignee as part of any reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer or other disposition of all or any portion of our business, assets or stock (including in bankruptcy or similar proceedings). 
  * If required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary: (a) under applicable law, including laws outside your country of residence; (b) to comply with legal process; (c) to respond to requests from public and government authorities, including public and government authorities outside your country of residence; (d) to enforce our terms and conditions; (e) to protect our operations or those of any of our affiliates; (f) to protect our rights, privacy, safety or property, and/or that of our affiliates, you or others; and (g) to allow us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain. 

We may use and disclose information that does not identify or otherwise relate to an individual for any purpose, except where we are required to do otherwise under applicable law. 

#### Children and Minors

The Services are not intended for children under the age of 13 and we do not knowingly collect or solicit Response Data or personal information from persons under the age of 13. If you are a parent or legal guardian who discovers that your child has provided us with any of the foregoing, you may contact us at support@tapresearch.com, and we will endeavor to promptly delete such information from our files. 

#### Information Security

We attempt to safeguard and protect your personal information from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction, through maintenance and use of reasonable security measures. However, please bear in mind and be aware that unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and the inherent insecure nature of the Internet, among other factors, may potentially compromise the security of your information at any given time. As such, we cannot make any guarantees as to the security of your information. 

#### Location of Data

We may transfer the information we collect about you to countries other than the country in which the information was originally collected. Please be advised, however, that such countries may not have the same data protection laws as the country in which you initially provided the information. We will protect your information as described in this Privacy Policy when we transfer such information to other countries. By using the Services, you consent to the collection, transfer, use, storage and disclosure of your information as described in this Privacy Policy, including to the export of your information outside of your country of residence. If you are accessing or using the Services from outside the United States, please be aware that your information, including any Response Data may be transferred to, stored, and processed in the United States. As a result, United States Federal and state governments, courts, or law enforcement or regulatory agencies may be able to obtain disclosure of your information, including Response Data, through applicable United States laws and regulations. 

#### EU-US Privacy Shield

TapResearch complies with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework established by the US Department of Commerce, under the enforcement authority of the Federal Trade Commission, regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from EU member countries. TapResearch has certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity and purpose limitation, access, and recourse, enforcement and liability. If there is any conflict between the policies in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. 

To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit http://www.privacyshield.gov/. To see a list of organizations participating in the Privacy Shield program, please visit https://www.privacyshield.gov/list. 

#### Third Party Links, Websites, and Services

This Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of companies that we do not own or control, or to individuals that we do not employ or manage, nor does it apply to your relationship with the third party web sites, applications, services, and surveys (including those of any Third Party MR Company) that may be linked to, facilitated through or provided via our Services. For example, our Services may be made available to you through third party mobile applications (including mobile games). If you use a third party application, website, or service or participate in a third party survey, then such third party's privacy policy will govern the use, storage and disclosure of your information in connection with such site, application, service, or survey. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of such third party sites, applications, services, and surveys nor any data or information you may share with such third parties. We encourage you to read the privacy policies applicable to each and every third party site, application, service, and survey prior to your access, use, or participation. TapResearch acknowledges there exists the potential for liability in cases of onward transfer to 3rd parties. 

#### Changes and Updates

We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you of such changes by posting the updated Privacy Policy on our Website. When we post changes to this Privacy Policy, we will revise the "last updated" date found at the top of this Privacy Policy. We recommend that you check this Privacy Policy periodically, to inform yourself of any changes to it. Your continued use of the Services after any changes or revisions to this Privacy Policy become effective will indicate your agreement with the terms of such revised Privacy Policy. 

#### Requests and Contact Information

In compliance with the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles, TapResearch commits to resolve complaints about our consumer's privacy and our collection or use of consumer's personal information. EU citizens with inquiries of complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact TapResearch at: 

Address: 

Attn: Data Privacy & Information Protection Officer   
1001 Laurel St.   
San Carlos, CA 94070 

Email: 

TapResearch has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles to the INSIGHTS ASSOCIATION PRIVACY SHIELD PROGRAM, a non-profit alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States and operated by the Insights Association. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit http://www.insightsassociation.org/get-support/privacy-shield-program/privacy-shield-eu-swiss-citizens-file-complaint for more information and to file a complaint.
